# **Sobirjon Mo'minov**

Address: kashkadarya Region, Uzbekistan | Email: <a href="mailto:msobirjon394@gmail.com">msobirjon394@gmail.com</a> | Phone: +998939085307

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/derrick-davis-602378331 | github: https://github.com/coinyx

### **Education**

Tashkent University of Information Technologies (TUIT)

Bachelor's Degree-Computer Science 04/2014 – 05/2018

### **Summary**

Full Stack Developer with over 6+ years of experience on modern Frontend and Backend Technologies. Consulting basic business models, realized pixel-perfect design, implemented scalable & maintainable components with clear requirements. Highly experienced, solution-oriented professional in overseeing all aspects of the SDLC from extensive analysis and design through deployment and team collaboration.

#### **Skills**

Programming languages: HTML/CSS, PHP, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Python,D3.js, Three.js

Frameworks & Libraries: Laravel, JQuery, React.js, Next.js, Vue.js

CSS Frameworks: Tailwind CSS, Material UI, ShadcnUi, RadixUI, NextUi, ChakraUI, Ant

Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Redis, SuperBase, FireBase

Development Tools: AWS, Mocha/Jest, Docker, Jenkins, Git, Babel, Agile/Scrum

## **Experience**

Uztelecom, Tashkent - Senior Full Stack Developer

Jan.2022 - Apr. 2024

- Spearheaded the development of a cloud-based asset management system in PHP, boosting team productivity by simplifying file sharing and reducing retrieval times by 40%.
- Championed a PHP 7 transition project for legacy applications, yielding a 25% improvement in processing efficiency and supporting forwarding-compatibility.
- Led the development of a new landing page utilizing lazy loading techniques, achieving a 50% faster loading speed and increasing customer satisfaction scores by 25% within the first quarter of deployment.
- Implemented complex UI components with React/TypeScript/Next.js, SCSS & Tailwind CSS.
- Involved in designing and developing Amazon EC2, Amazon S3, Amazon RDS, Amazon Elastic Load Balancing.

Skytech solutions. Tashkent - Full Stack Developer

Auguest.2018 - Dec. 2020

- Launched a full-stack feature set for user-generated content moderation that reduced the manual review workload by 70% while maintaining community guidelines compliance.
- Developed sophisticated UI components using React, TypeScript, and Next.js, employing SCSS for advanced styling and Tailwind CSS for responsive design. Enhanced user experience and streamlined development with a focus on maintainability and performance.
- Rebuilt 4 year old Saas application in React and Redux with full user experience redesign to release a beta MVP in 8 months.
- Developed and optimized a modular codebase by implementing reusable components and design patterns, which enhanced code maintainability, reduced development time by up to 30%, and achieved a 20% reduction in bug rates.
- Integrated an automated property valuation model fed by machine learning Python Data

## Finetechlab, Tashkent - Junior Full Stack Developer

June. 2016 - Jul. 2018

- Collaborated with the backend team to design, define, and implement GraphQL types and resolvers to provide the necessary data for frontend development while maintaining calls to the database.
- Collaborated with backend and DevOps engineers for the release of new applications and new API endpoints with Node.js/Express.
- Good experience with JDBC drivers to perform operations such as CRUD operations with Reat.js/Next.js and writing complex queries with PostgresSQL, MongoDB and SQL Server.
- Improved the UI using Material UI, Bootstrap

## **Project**

https://bbbkings.vercel.app/ , https://hub.kryptomon.co/sign-in,